NABILA ABRAHAM









ABOUT ME

I'm an applied R&D data scientist interested in graph neural network/ social network analysis problems. In my spare time, I try to sharpen my skillset by mentoring budding data scientists & volunteering with AISC to breakdown state of the art research with the ML community.

SKILLS

- Python, SQL, Bash, MATLAB
- GCP, Azure, AWS EC2
- PyTorch, Keras, Git, ROS
- Basic webdev, Django, Flask

EDUCATION RYERSON UNIVERSITY

MASc. in Electrical & Computer Engineering 2017 – 2019 | Toronto, ON MASc thesis: Towards improved medical image segmentation

- Developed a custom loss function for class imbalance (over 100+ citations)
- Proposed a multimodal framework to improve feature extraction for segmentation

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

B.Eng in Biomedical
Engineering
2012 – 2017 | Toronto, ON
Capstone thesis: Wireless
intraoperative neuromonitoring
system for spinal surgery

PUBLICATIONS

Please view my <u>Google Scholar</u> for a detailed list

WORK EXPERIENCE

Loblaw Companies Canada | Data Scientist (R&D)

February 2020 – Present

- Investigating graph neural networks for entity resolution on Data
 Science Health & Identity Data Management teams
- Working to productionize MVP graph solutions via neo4j
- Leading Research Huddles, a company initiative to share applied R&D ideas, keep on top of state-of-the-art research & consult on ML projects

Lunenfeld-Tanenbaum Research Institute (Sinai Health

System) | Deep Learning Researcher July 2019 – January 2020

- Developed deep learning models for prostate cancer detection
- Provided 3d CAM/neural network visualizations for clinical team
- Co-authored a publication regarding clinical decision making on prostate cancer detection with supervised 3d CNNs

Ryerson Multimedia Lab | Graduate Student Researcher Sept 2017 – Oct 2019

- Investigated loss functions and generative models to improve semantic segmentation of medical data
- Partnered with Shaftesbury VR to develop predictive cues on player stress using time series analysis on biomedical signals (patent pending)

TEACHING/MENTORSHIP

SharpestMinds | Data Science Mentor

March 2020 - Present

- Mentoring data scientists to create industry relevant portfolios in the fields of healthcare and retail
- Testimonials & badges relating to "intuitive explanations" and "helpful introductions" available on my profile here (sign up required)

UofT School of Continuing Education | Assistant Instructor Nov 2020 – Present

 Teaching a cohort of 30+ adult learners the concepts of Git, Python, SQL, CNNs, RNNs, Gradient boosting, PCA, NLP via AWS, Blockchain & more in a 6-month long FinTech bootcamp

VOLUNTEER

GNN Stream Owner | Aggregate Intellect Socratic Circles Feb 2020 – Present

 Organize monthly graph neural network themed talks with authors and enable a wider discussion on YouTube Live Stream

Ryerson Rams Robotics Team | Machine Learning Mentor IEEE Ryerson Chapter | Graduate Student Representative